University Senate; Records ua200
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Councils and Committees, 1950-2011; 15; 16.69 cubic ft.
  - Graduate Academic Council (GAC), 1961-2023; 15.3; 9.67 cubic ft.
    - Minutes, 2011 March 25
    - Agenda, 2011 April 4
    - Agenda, 2011 April 8
    - Minutes, 2011 April 8
    - Agenda, 2011 April 29
    - Minutes, 2011 April 29
    - Agenda, 2011 May 4
    - Agenda, 2011 May 9
    - Minutes, 2011 May 9
    - Agenda, 2011 September 30
    - Minutes, 2011 September 30
    - Agenda, 2011 November 16
    - Minutes, 2011 November 16
    - Agenda, 2011 December 16
    - Minutes, 2011 December 16
    - Minutes, 2012 February 6
    - Minutes, 2012 March 6
    - Minutes, 2012 April 4
    - Minutes, 2012 May 4
    - Agenda, 2012 September 21
    - Minutes, 2012 September 21
    - Agenda, 2012 October 15
    - Minutes, 2012 October 15
    - Agenda, 2012 November 12
    - Minutes, 2012 November 12
    - Agenda, 2012 December 21
    - Minutes, 2012 December 21
    - Agenda, 2013 March 12
    - Minutes, 2013 March 12
    - Agenda, 2013 April 12
    - Minutes, 2013 April 12
    - Agenda, 2013 May 9
    - Minutes, 2013 May 9
    - Agenda, 2013 September 17
    - Minutes, 2013 September 17
    - Minutes, 2013 November 15
    - Minutes, 2013 December 13
    - Minutes, 2014 March 11
    - Minutes, 2014 April 8
    - Minutes, 2014 April 29
    - Minutes, 2014 May 9
    - Agenda, 2014 September 9
    - Minutes, 2014 October 21
    - Minutes, 2014 November 18
    - Draft Minutes, 2014 December 15
    - Draft Minutes, 2015 March 3
    - Draft Minutes, 2015 April 7
    - Minutes, 2015 April 28
    - Minutes, 2015 May 12
    - Minutes, 2015 September 28
    - Minutes, 2015 October 19
    - Minutes, 2015 November 16
    - Minutes, 2016 February 8
    - Minutes, 2016 March 2
    - Minutes, 2016 April 6
    - Minutes, 2016 April 29
    - Minutes, 2016 September 21
    - Minutes, 2016 October 24
    - Minutes, 2016 November 21
    - Minutes, 2016 December 5
    - Minutes, 2017 February 17
    - Minutes, 2017 March 10
    - Minutes, 2017 April 3
    - Minutes, 2017 April 17
    - Minutes, 2017 May 8
    - Agenda, 2017 September 26
    - Minutes, 2017 September 26
    - Agenda, 2017 October 13
    - Minutes, 2017 October 13
    - Agenda, 2017 October 31
    - Minutes, 2017 October 31
    - Agenda, 2017 December 5
    - Minutes, 2017 December 5
    - Agenda, 2018 February 15
    - Minutes, 2018 February 15
    - Agenda, 2018 March 1
    - Minutes, 2018 March 1
    - Agenda, 2018 April 19
    - Minutes, 2018 April 19
    - Agenda, 2018 May 10
    - Minutes, 2018 May 10
    - Agenda, 2018 October 1
    - Minutes, 2018 October 1
    - Agenda, 2018 October 22
    - Minutes, 2018 October 22
    - Agenda, 2018 November 19
    - Minutes, 2018 November 19
    - Agenda, 2018 December 10
    - Minutes, 2018 December 10
    - Agenda, 2019 February 1
    - Minutes, 2019 February 1
    - Agenda, 2019 February 28
    - Agenda, 2019 March 7
    - Minutes, 2019 March 7
    - Agenda, 2019 April 18
    - Minutes, 2019 April 18
    - Agenda, 2019 May 9
    - Minutes, 2019 May 9
    - Agenda, 2019 September 20
    - Minutes, 2019 September 20
    - Agenda, 2019 October 17
    - Minutes, 2019 October 17
    - Agenda, 2019 November 15
    - Minutes, 2019 November 15
    - Agenda, 2019 December 9
    - Minutes, 2019 December 9
    - Agenda, 2020 January 31
    - Minutes, 2020 January 31
    - Agenda, 2020 February 24
    - Minutes, 2020 February 24
    - Minutes, 2020 March 23
    - Agenda, 2020 April 10
    - Minutes, 2020 April 10
    - Agenda, 2020 May 8
    - Minutes, 2020 May 8
    - Agenda, 2020 October 7
    - Minutes, 2020 October 7
    - Agenda, 2020 November 4
    - Minutes, 2020 November 4
    - Agenda, 2020 December 2
    - Minutes, 2020 December 2
    - Agenda, 2021 January 11
    - Minutes, 2021 January 11
    - Agenda, 2021 February 8
    - Minutes, 2021 February 8
    - Agenda, 2021 March 8
    - Minutes, 2021 March 8
    - Agenda, 2021 April 5
    - Minutes, 2021 April 5
    - Agenda, 2021 May 3
    - Minutes, 2021 May 3
    - Agenda, 2021 October
    - Minutes, 2021 October
    - Agenda, 2021 November
    - Minutes, 2021 November
    - Agenda, 2021 December
    - Minutes, 2021 December
    - Agenda, 2022 February
    - Minutes, 2022 February
    - Agenda, 2022 March
    - Minutes, 2022 March
    - Agenda, 2022 April
    - Minutes, 2022 April
    - Agenda, 2022 May
    - Minutes, 2022 May
    - Agenda, 2022 September
    - Minutes, 2022 September 20
    - Agenda, 2022 October
    - Minutes, 2022 October 13
    - Agenda, 2022 November
    - Minutes, 2022 November 8
    - Agenda, 2022 December
    - Minutes, 2022 December 1
    - Agenda, 2023 February
  - Undergraduate Academic Council (UAC), 1950-2010; 15.4; 4 cubic ft.
    Arranged alphabetically and chronologically thereafter. T
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Agendas and Minutes, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Meeting Minutes-Approved, 2010-02-10
    - Meeting Minutes-Revised by Committee, 2010-02-10
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009-12-03
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009-12-10
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010-04-28
    - UAC's thoughts on the new Gen Ed Task Force proposed by the SEC, 2010-01
  - Council on Research (COR), 1966-2019; 15.5; 0.5 cubic ft.
    Includes agendas, minutes, annual reports, reports to the Senate, and correspondence. The Research Council is empowered to review research activities, to consider ways in which the University can increase the effectiveness of its research activities, to review procedures of research conducted on campus when human subjects are involved, to set safety standards, and to allocate research funds within the university.
    Also includes the records of committees and policies of the Research Council. The Research Council has drafted the SUNYA Research Policy (1970), the Human Subjects Policy (1977), formed the Biohazards Committee (1977), established funding for research, and instituted the Writing Center (1978). Included in the series are the records of the Recombinant DNA Research Committee.
    - Council on Research Membership, 2018-2019
    - Agenda, 2018 September
    - Minutes, 2018 September
    - Agenda, 2018 October
    - Minutes, 2018 October
    - Agenda, 2018 November
    - Minutes, 2018 November
    - Agenda, 2018 December
    - Minutes, 2018 December
    - Minutes, 2019 January
    - Agenda, 2019 January
    - Minutes, 2019 March 4
    - Revised Agenda, 2019 March 4
    - Agenda, 2019 March 25
    - Minutes, 2019 March 25
    - Minutes, 2019 April
    - Agenda, 2019 April
    - Minutes - ICR Addendum, 2019 May
    - Agenda, 2019 May
    - Council on Research Membership, 2004-2005
    - Council on Research Subcommittees, 2009-2010
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 April 7
    - Agenda, 2010 May 3
    - Agenda, 2010 February 3
    - Agenda, 2010 March 3
    - Agenda, 2010 April 7
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 May 18
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 February 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 May 3
    - Agenda, 2011 February 16
    - Agenda, 2011 March 16
    - Agenda, 2011 April 27
    - Agenda, 2011 May 18
    - Agenda, 2010 September 15
    - Agenda, 2010 October 20
    - Agenda, 2010 November 17
    - Agenda, 2010 December 15
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 April 17
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 December 15
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 February 16
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 16
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 November 16
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 October 20
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 September 15
    - Council on Research Membership, 2010-2011
  - Council on Promotions & Continuing Appointments (CPCA), 1967-2011; 15.6; 0.5 cubic ft.
    This series includes minutes, annual reports, bills and resolutions, and correspondence. The council recommends individuals for promotions in rank and for continuing appointment ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p.26).
    Also includes the records of CPCA committees. These include the Faculty Evaluation & Personnel Action Committee (1970), the Faculty-Student Committee on Tenure (1968-69), and the Subcommittee on Promotions and Continuing Appointments (1972-74).
    - Membership List, 2004-2005
    - Membership List, 2010-2011
  - Committee on Academic Freedom, Freedom of Expression, & Community Responsibility (CAFFECoR), 1972-1998; 15.7; 0.5 cubic ft.
    This series contains agendas and minutes (1972-98) and reports to the Senate (1972-82). The Council considers problems and recommends policies concerning matters of academic freedom and standards of professional ethics both inside and outside the university community (Faculty Handbook, 1984, p 25.) The Council on Academic Freedom and Ethics deals with matters concerning student grievances and professional codes of ethics. The predecessor of the Council on Academic Freedom and Ethics was the Committee on Academic Freedom of the Faculty Council (Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 16).
    - Membership List, 2004-2005
    - Membership List, 2010-2011
  - Council on Libraries, Information Systems, & Computing (LISC), 1966-2011; 15.8; 0.5 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas and minutes, annual reports, bills and resolutions, correspondence, and reports to the Senate. The responsibilities of the Library Council include establishing policies for the library and guidelines for its development and selecting candidates for the Excellence in Librarianship Award ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 26). The Council has considered policy measures regarding the schedule for fines, budget planning, growth of library, acquisition and circulation, and providing searching on bibliographic utilities. In 1988, the title of the Council was changed from Library Council to Council on Libraries, Computing and Information Systems, and its responsibilities were expanded to "review plans for and recommend policies for the development and operation of informational systems and technology as well as for library facilities" ( Faculty Handbook, 1989-90, p. 25).
    - Agenda, 2010 May 3
    - Agenda, 2009 December 7
    - Minutes, 2009 November 9
    - Agenda, 2010 February 1
    - Minutes, 2010 April 5
    - Minutes, 2010 May 3
    - Minutes, 2009 September 21
    - Minutes, 2009 October 12
    - Minutes, 2009 May 8
    - Agenda, 2011 February 14
    - Minutes, 2010 December 13
    - Minutes, 2011 February 14
    - Minutes, 2010 November 15
    - Minutes, 2010 October 8
    - Minutes, 2011 April 11
    - Minutes, 2011 March 14
    - Minutes, 2011 May 9
    - Membership, 2011-2011
  - University Life Council (ULC), 2005-2011; 15.9
    - Research Tool Changes Senate Bill Complete, 2005-2006
    - IRB Exempt Human Subjects Review, 2005-2006
    - UACGAC StandAcaIntegrity, 2005-2006
    - Mand Insurance, 2005-2006
    - Misconduct Policy, 2005-2006
    - Diversity Presentaion, 2005-2006
    - Senate Meeting, 2005-2006
    - Create Athletics Position, 2005-2006
    - Resolution 05 Family Leave, 2005-2006
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 October 6
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 September 29
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 April 27; 2011 April 17
    - Meeting Minutes Revised by Committee, 2010 October 6
    - Meeting Minutes Revised by Committee, 2010 October 13; 2010 October 21
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 March 9
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 March 16
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 September 15
    - Meeting Minutes Revised by Committee, 2010 September 29; 2010 October 05
    - Membership, 2010-2011
    - Meeting Scheule and Sub-Committees Assignments, 2010-2011
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 November 10
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 November 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 November 03
    - Membership, 2009-2010
  - University Planning and Policy Council (UPPC), 2004-2011; 15.10
    - Working Minutes, 2005-2006
    - Membership, 2010-2011
    - 4x4 Report 1996, 2004-2005
    - College of Computing and Information FAQs, 2004-2005
    - Proposal for Advanced Certificate in Economic Forecasting Letter, 2004-2005
    - Statement for the Graduate Bulletin Describing the Proposed Graduate Certificate in Economic Forecasting, 2004-2005
    - Advanced Certificate in Economic Forecasting Proposed, 2004-2005
    - Gen*NY*Sis Center for Excellence in Cancer Genomics Operating Plan, 2004-2005
    - Honor's College Proposal, 2004-2005
    - Institutional Response to 1998 Task Force Summary Institutional Response to 1998 Task Force, 2004-2005
    - Memorandum from President Ryan, 2004-2005
    - Satisfaction SurveyTrends by SUNY factors, 2004-2005
    - SUNY-Wide Comparitive Ratings, 2004-2005
    - UPC Fall Academic Calendar Legislation, 2004-2005
    - Agenda, 2005 January 24
    - Agenda, 2004 October 11
    - Agenda, 2004 November 1
    - Agenda, 2004 November 29
    - Agenda, 2005 February 7
    - Agenda, 2005 March 7
    - Agenda, 2005 April 4
    - Agenda, 2005 May 2
    - Agenda, 2004 September 27
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 January 24
    - Approved Minutes, 2004 October 11
    - Approved Minutes, 2004 November 1
    - Approved Minutes, 2004 November 29
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 April 25
    - Approved Minutes, 2004 September 27
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 February 7
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 March 28
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 March 7
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 April 18
    - Approved Minutes, 2005 April 4
    - Working Minutes, 2005 May 2
    - Working Minutes, 2005 April 18
    - UPC Members, 2005-2006
    - Memo to President Philip, 2010 March 29
    - Minutes, 2010 April 23
    - Minutes, 2010 April 9
    - Report from University Policy & Planning Council, 2010-2011
    - Meeting Minutes, 2011 March 25
    - Meeting Minutes Revised, 2011 May 6
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 September 17
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 October 29
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 December 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 December 17
  - Council on Academic Assessment (CAA), 2004-2011; 15.11
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 June 28
    - Meeting Minutes, 2004 December 1
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 May 6
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 November 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 December 15
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 February 4
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 March 4
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 April 15
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 July 27
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 November 7
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 December 5
    - Meeting Minutes, 2006 March 2
    - Meeting Minutes, 2006 April 4
    - Meeting Minutes, 2006 May 30
    - Meeting Minutes, 2005 September 26
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 April 24
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 April 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 March 6
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 May 19
    - Meeting Minutes, 2007 November 7
    - Meeting Minutes, 2007 September 20
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 April 1
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 April 29
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 December 3
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 February 25
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 February 4
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 March 11
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 November 19
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 November 5
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 October 15
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 October 29
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 September 17
    - Meeting Minutes, 2008 September 24
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 April 14
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 April 22
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 10
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 March 25
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 November 16
    - Meeting Minutes, 2009 November 4
    - Charter Amendment, 2010-2011
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 21
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 September 29
    - Senate Charter Amendment, 2010 April 22
    - Agenda, 2010 October 27
    - Agenda, 2010 December 14
    - Agenda, 2011 February 18
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 December 14
    - Meeting Minutes, 2010 November 17
    - General Education Task Force, 2011 November 23
    - Membership, 2010-2011
  - Committee on Ethics in Research and Scholarship (CERS), 2010-2011; 15.12
    - Membership List, 2010-2011
  - Council on Educational Policy, 1963-1998; 15.13; 4.5 cubic ft.
    This series contains agendas, minutes, correspondence, budget proposals, reports to the Senate, reports from sub-committees and other councils and memoranda relating to the council's responsibility for the oversight of campus planning and for the establishment of educational priorities. The council participates in the formulation and execution of the campus budget and evaluates the educational performance of the University as a whole and of its various components ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, pp. 18-19). Issues under consideration by the council include the budget, academic regulations, the curriculum, faculty work load, teaching excellence, enrollment and class size. The Council was originally created by the Graduate Council as a standing committee in 1961/62. The Council has three standing Committees, the Long-Range Planning Committee, the Resource Advisory Committee (formerly the Resource Allocation Committee), and the Evaluation Policy Committee (formerly the Program Evaluation Committee).
  - Student Affairs Council, 1966-1995; 15.14; 0.33 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas, minutes, annual reports, reports to the Senate, bills and resolutions, and correspondence. This series also includes the records of the Interfaith Committee and the International Students Committee. The Council's concerns are to develop policies necessary to establish and maintain extracurricular programs and to make recommendations concerning University policy affecting student activities in these programs ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 23). The Student Affairs council has dealt with the issues of campus relations, university communications (1971), alumni affairs, alcohol policy, student conduct, inspection of student housing (1973), policy regarding student records, campus ambulance service (1972-1973), and the SUNYA judicial system (1972-80). The Student Affairs Council was the successor to the Student Personnel Council, a college council independent of the Faculty Council ( Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 20).
  - University Community Council, 1967-1998; 15.15; 0.75 cubic ft.
    This series includes agendas, minutes, annual reports, bills and legislation, correspondence, and reports to the Senate of the University Community Council. The council oversees university-wide matters, non-academic in nature, including external communications, operation of the University Auxiliary Service, and such policies affecting public safety, transportation, parking, etc. ( Faculty Handbook, 1984, p. 24). The predecessor to the University Community Council was the Committee on Community Liaison of the Faculty Council ( Faculty Handbook, 1962, p. 16).
    Also includes the records of the committees and policies established by the University Community Council. The University Community Council establishes policies regarding traffic and parking control, campus firearms policy (1973), the carrying of guns by security personnel, aesthetics of the campus environment, the skating rink proposal (1973), emeritus faculty privileges (1973), the 1970's gasoline shortage and its effects on the University, recycling programs, pets on campus, and the smoking policy(1996).
  - Distinguished Teaching Professor (DTP) and Distinguished Service Professor (DSP) Committee, 2011-2012
    - Previous Guidelines for DTP and DSP Selection Committee, 2007-2008
    - Excellence Award Recipients, 1973-2011
    - UAlbany Selection Committee for Promotions to DTP and DSP, 2011-2012
  - Ad Hoc Revenue Committee, 2010-2011
    - Ad Hoc Revenue Committee Members List, 2010-2011
    - Correspondence Regarding Committee to Create Additional Funding Opportunities for UAlbany, 2010-11-17
  - Budget Advisory Group (BAG) IV, 2010-2011
    - Student Success and Reduction Data, 2011 March 7
    - BAG IV Division of Research Budget Reductions Presentation, 2010-2011
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 21
    - Meeting Report, 2011 April 5
    - Research Division Presentation, 2011 April 5
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 14
    - BAG IV Communications & Marketing Presentation, 2011 March 11
    - BAG IV Final Report, 2011 April 15
    - Description of the Relationship Between the University at Albany and the College of Nanoscale Sciences and Engineering, 2010-2011
    - Comparative Data, 2011 March 4
    - Academic Affairs Culmative Reductions, 2011 March 9
    - BAG IV Membership, 2010-2011
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 28
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 4
    - Meeting Report, 2011 February 22
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 11
    - Meeting Report, 2011 March 10
    - Report to University Senate and Senate Executive Committee, 2011 February 11; 2011 February 14
    - National Study of Instructional Costs and Productivity, 2011 March 4
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 March 20-2011 March 26
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 March 27-2011 April 2
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 April 10-2011 April 16
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 April 17-2011 April 23
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 April 24-2011 April 30
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 April 3-2011 April 9
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 May 1-2011 May 7
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 May 15-2011 May 21
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 May 22-2011 May 28
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 May 8-2011 May 14
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 June 21-2011 June 27
    - Webtracking Report, 2011 June 5-2011 June 11